Ryan Lugtu

Full-Stack Developer

Hackensack, NJ ryanlugtu@gmail.com ryanlugtu.com linkedin.com/in/ryan-lugtu github.com/rlugtu

Personal

Passionate and goal-oriented developer transitioning from the healthcare field to the tech industry. Empowered by innovation and design to deliver high-quality digital experiences by utilizing skills gained from healthcare such as creative problem-solving, team collaboration, and effective communication.

Skills

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript/ES6, EJS, REST, Ruby, SQL, PostgreSQL

Frameworks & Libraries: React, Express, Node.js, Material UI, Firebase

Technologies & Deployment: Heroku, Netlify, Git, Trello, Postman, Yarn, NPM

Experience

Web Developer, Freelance

2020-Present

- Worked with each client to create a roadmap in order to gather client specifications of new or existing websites
- Designed, built, and deployed business websites using HTML, CSS, React, and JavaScript
- Refactored existing websites to implement features requested by client

Ivy Rehab Physical Therapy, Physical Therapist Aide Twin Boro Physical Therapy, Physical Therapist Aide

2019 - 2020

2017 - 2019

- Responsible for assisting 20-30 patients per day by applying heat packs, paraffin dips, helping patients onto exercise equipment, monitoring motion, performing prescribed exercises and strengthening techniques
- Electronically scheduled patient appointments, recorded patient progress, and updated fitness programs

Projects

Welp | welpme.herokuapp.com/ | github.com/rlugtu/welp | Full-Stack Developer

- Full-stack business directory SAAS application that allows users to search, bookmark, and review services
- Integrated the Yelp Fusion API to provide business information based on search queries made by users
- Front-end wireframes designed with Adobe XD and converted into web pages using ReactJS
- Implemented server/client-side communication RESTful API using Ruby on Rails, SQL, and PostgreSQL
- Technologies: React, Ruby on Rails, Material UI, SQL, PostgreSQL

FitPal | fitpaltracker.herokuapp.com/ | github.com/rlugtu/fitpals | Full-Stack Developer

- Full Stack Express SAAS application that allows users to create, schedule, edit, and delete workout sessions
- Front-end programmed and rendered with Embedded JavaScript Templates(EJS); animations with CSS
- Implemented server/client-side communication with REST API using Express, SQL, and PostgreSQL
- Technologies: Javascript, EJS, Express, SQL, PostgreSQL

EZBuild | github.com/rlugtu/EZBuild | *Full-Stack Developer*

- Collaborated in a team to create a full-stack application allowing users to create personalized computers
- Built front-end React components and architecture; built back-end API using Express, SQL, and PostgreSQL
- Acted as project manager for the group ensuring that deliverables were met
- Utilized a Trello board and Slack group messenger to track outstanding and completed tasks
- Technologies: React, Express, PostgreSQL, SQL

Education

General Assembly | Software Engineering Immersive

Participated in 500+ hours of applied training in software engineering and web development concepts focusing on both front-end and back-end development. Participated in pair-programming to assure and improve code quality. Participated in group collaboration on daily coding exercises as well as one main project

Rutgers University | Bachelor of Science, Kinesiology